Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Clement Greenberg papers
1937-1983
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Greenberg, Clement
8.6 linear feet
The papers of art critic, author, and lecturer Clement Greenberg measure 8.6 linear feet and date from 1937 to 1983. The bulk of the collection consists of letters from art critics, artists, family, friends, galleries, and museums. Notable correspondents include Jack Bush, Anthony Caro, Richard Diebenkorn, Friedel Dzubas, Helen Frankenthaler, Adolph Gottlieb, Hans Hofmann, Morris Louis, Robert Motherwell, Charles Pollock, Jules Olitski, David Smith, and Anne Truitt among others. Also found are biograpical materials, personal business and financial records, an etching by Kurt Wisneski, printed materials, and two reports by Greenberg concerning his travels.
Provenance
Clement Greenberg donated his papers in several accretions between 1984 to 1991.
Separated Material
Clement Greenberg loaned papers for microfilming on reels N69-91, N70-7, and N737 between 1968-1969. Most, but not all, of these papers were later donated by Greenberg.
Related Material
The Portland Art Museum holds Clement Greenberg's private art collection as well as a library of exhibition catalogs.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of the papers were originally microfilmed as loans and are still available on microfilm reels N69-91, N70-7, and N737. The arrangement of the papers on microfilm does not match the current arrangement of the papers.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Some of the collection is ACCESS RESTRICTED: documents relating to the estate of David Smith; some correspondence with Peter Fuller, Nuala O'Faolain, and the Greenberg family; and sale and loan agreements. Contact the reference staff for more information about permission to use this portion of the collection.
Biographical Note
Clement Greenberg was a highly influential art critic working in New York City from the 1940s through the 1960s. He was an advocate of modern art, particulary the abstract expressionist movement, and one of the first critics to recognize the significance of Jackson Pollock's work.
Greenberg was born in 1909 to Russian immigrants in Bronx, New York. After graduating from Syracuse University in 1930, he married and had a child, David. He settled in New York City while working at the United States Customs Department as an appraiser.
In the late 1930s, Clement Greenberg attended a meeting of the U.S. Works Progress Administration and heard Hans Hofmann speak of avant-garde art. In 1939, he wrote one of his first important critical pieces "Avant-Garde and Kitsch" for the Partisan Review. Greenberg argued that the avant-garde art movement rose out of the need to defend and maintain high art standards against the decline in taste brought about by America's consumerism and capitalist culture.
In 1940, Greenberg joined Partisan Review as an editor. He became art critic for the Nation in 1942, and was associate editor of Commentary from 1945 until 1957. In December 1950, he joined the CIA-fronted American Committee for Cultural Freedom.
Throughout the 1940s through the 1960s Greenberg continued to write and, in his essays and articles, he promoted the work of Abstract Expressionists, among them Jackson Pollock, Willem de Kooning, Hans Hofmann, Barnett Newman, and Clyfford Still. He particularly championed Jackson Pollock. Greenberg wrote several seminal essays that defined his views on art history in the 20th century. "Greenberg on Collage" was one one of his most important.
Greenberg's views on pop art were mixed. He also became less enamored with Abstract Impressionism, particularly the second generation. However, he became very interested in the Color-Field and Hard-Edge painters.
Through the 1960s Greenberg's views informed a younger generation of art critics including Michael Fried and Rosalind E. Krauss. Some writers maintain that Greenberg's views were so well-respected that he had too much of an influence on the world of art. In time, Greenberg's antagonism to Postmodernist theories and other modern art movements caused him to lose much of his credibility among both artists and art critics.
Greenberg died at the age of eighty-five in 1994.
Since his death, letters edited by his widow, Janice Van Horne and a re-evaluation of his writings have helped to restore his reputation within the art world.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of influential New York art critic Clement Greenberg measure 8.6 linear feet and date from 1937 to 1983. The bulk of the papers (7 feet) consists of letters from art critics, artists, family, friends, galleries, and museums, with some letters from Greenberg. Correspondents include Edward Avedisian, Darby Bannard, Ethel Baziotes, Jack Bush, Anthony Caro, Gene Davis, Richard Diebenkorn, Piero Dorazio, Friedel Dzubas, Andre Emmerich, Paul Feeley, Sam Francis, Helen Frankenthaler, Robert Goodnough, Adolf Gottleib, Hans Hofmann, Philippe Hosiasson, Jacob Kainen, Rosalind Krauss, Robert Motherwell, Ken Moffett, Barnett Newman, Kenneth Noland, Jules Olitski, Beverly Pepper, Ludwig Sander, David Smith, Kimber Smith, Clyfford Still, Anne Truitt, and Leslie Waddington.
Biographical materials include a transcript of an interview with Greenberg conducted by Deborah Solomon in 1983. Greenberg's personal business and financial records include correspondence regarding his lectures and seminars, requests for his writings, student queries, documents regarding his television and radio appearances, royalty statements, and receipts for gifts of works of art. Also found within business records are documents relating to Greenberg's testimony at the Mark Rothko Trial in 1974.
Artwork consists of one etching by Kurt Wisenski entitled "Spring." The papers contain very few of Greenberg's writings about art. Found are lists of artists, and reports written by Greenberg on the state of art in Japan and India in 1967, likely related to his membership in the American Committee for Cultural Freedom. Printed material includes scattered clippings concerning art and exhibition announcements.
One series of ACCESS RESTRICTED papers contains documents relating to Greenberg's role as a trustee in the David Smith estate; correspondence between Greenberg with Andre Emmerich and Peter Fuller, Nuala O'Faolain, and the Greenberg family; and some financial materials regarding the sale and loan of Greenberg's art collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Information, circa 1950s-1983 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Business and Financial Records, 1940-1983 (Box 1; 12 folders)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1937-1983 (Boxes 1-8; 7 linear feet)
Series 4: Artwork, 1973 (Box 8; 1 folder)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, 1967-1983 (Box 8; 3 folders)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1950-1982 (Box 8; 2 folders)
Series 7: Restricted Material, 1963-1983 (Boxes 9-11; 1.2 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970; Smith, David, 1906-1965
Subjects-Topical:
Art -- Economic aspects; Art -- India; Art -- Japan; Art criticism -- New York (State) -- New York; Art critics -- New York (State) -- New York; Modernism (Art) -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Etchings; Interviews; Photographs; Reports; Transcripts
Names:
Avedisian, Edward, 1936-2007; Bannard, Walter Darby, 1934-; Baziotes, Ethel; Bush, Jack, 1909-; Caro, Anthony, 1924-; Connolly, Cyril, 1903-1974; Davis, Gene, 1920-1985; Diebenkorn, Richard, 1922-; Dorazio, Piero, 1927-; Dzubas, Friedel, 1915-; Emmerich, André; Feeley, Paul, 1910-1966; Francis, Sam, 1923-1994; Frankenthaler, Helen, 1928-; Fuller, Peter, 1947-1990; Goodnough, Robert, 1917-; Gottlieb, Adolph, 1903-1974; Hofmann, Hans, 1880-1966; Hosaisson, Philippe; Kainen, Jacob; Krauss, Rosalind E.; Moffett, Kenworth; Motherwell, Robert; Newman, Barnett, 1905-1970; Noland, Kenneth, 1924-; O'Faolin, Nuala; Olitski, Jules, 1922-2007; Pepper, Beverly; Sander, Ludwig, 1906-; Smith, David, 1906-1965; Smith, Kimber, 1922-1981; Solomon, Deborah; Still, Clyfford, 1904-; Truitt, Anne, 1921-; Waddington, Leslie; Wisenski, Kurt; American Committee for Cultural Freedom
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Information, circa 1950s-1983, Series 1:; (Box 1; 2 folders)
  Found here are invitations to a dinner honoring Clement Greenberg in 1968, two slides from Mary Frances Judge's "Tribute to a Critic" from 1971, various certificates awarded to Greenberg and a transcript from an interview with Greenberg conducted by Deborah Solomon in 1983.
  - Clement Greenberg, circa 1950s-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Deborah Solomon (transcript), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Business and Financial Records, 1948-1983, Series 2:; (Box 1; 12 folders)
  Records include correspondence and other documents relating to Greenberg's testimony at the Mark Rothko trial including a subpoena for Greenberg and scattered correspondence; requests for lectures and seminars; recepits and acknowledgements for Greenberg's donations; requests for Greenberg's writings including articles, essays, and television and radio appearances; royalty statements; and queries for Greenberg from students.
  - Interviews, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lectures and Seminars, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lectures and Seminars, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lectures and Seminars, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lectures and Seminars, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lectures and Seminars, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mark Rothko Trial, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Receipts and Acknowledgements of Gifts, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reprint Permissions, 1939-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Requests for Articles, 1948-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Requests for Catalog Essays, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Royalty Statements, 1974-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Student Queries, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Television and Radio Appearances, 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1937-1983, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-8; 7.0 linear feet)
  Correspondence includes letters to Greenberg and scattered replies. The bulk of letters are from artists, galleries, museums, and publications although some personal correspondence is found. Notable correspondents include: Edward Avedisian, Darby Bannard, Ethel Baziotes, Jack Bush, Anthony Caro, Gene Davis, Richard Diebenkorn, Piero Dorazio, Friedel Dzubas, Andre Emmerich, Paul Feeley, Sam Francis, Helen Frankenthaler, Robert Goodnough, Adolf Gottleib, Hans Hofmann, Philippe Hosiasson, Jacob Kainen, Rosalind Krauss, Ken Moffett, Barnett Newman, Kenneth Noland, Jules Olitski, Beverly Pepper, Ludwig Sander, David Smith, Kimber Smith, Clyfford Still, Anne Truitt, and Leslie Waddington among others. Correspondence between Peter Fuller, Andre Emmerich, and Clement Greenberg; Nuala O'Faolain; and the Greenberg family are access restricted.
  - Abadie, Daniel, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Abelove, Martin, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Abrahamsen, David, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Abram, Dario, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Abrams, Henry N., 1964-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ackerman, Paul, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Acquarella Galleries, Inc., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Adams, Harriet, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Adams, Patricia, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Agnew, Ella, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Allemandi, Umberto, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Allen Center Competition, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Alloway, Lawrence, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Allsopp, Judy, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ambadas, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Aminoff, Judith, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Andersen, Wayne, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Andrus, Stephen, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Archives of American Art, 1965-1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ardron, Cindy, 1980-1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Arnold, Marion, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Art and Culture, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Art Forum, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Art in America, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Art International, 1961-1981 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Art Net, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Art News, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Art Students League of New York, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Arts Magazine, 1957-1973 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Ashton, Dore, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Association for the Support and Diffusion of Art, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Atkinson, Ti-Grace, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Audette, Yvonne, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Auger, Boyd, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Australia, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Avedisian, Edward, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Ayers, Larry, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - A, 1968-1983 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Baer, Martha, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Baiz, Hetty, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Baker, Lucy, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Bannard, Darby, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Barker, Ian, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Baro, Gene, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Baziotes, Ethel, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Beacon Press, 1955-1979 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Bennington College, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Bentham, Douglas, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Berman, Esmie, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Bernstein, Vanessa, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Bewley, Marius, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Bireline, George/Jan, 1963-1983 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Birnbaum, Norman, 1956-1983 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Birt, Christopher, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bishop, Budd, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Black Mountain College, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Bloore, Ron, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Boepple, Willard, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Bois, Yve-Alain, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Bolaffi Arte, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Bongard, William, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Bornstein, Eli, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Bowling, Frank, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Brenner, Ardeth, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Bressler, Martin, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Britt, David, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Brockton Art Center, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Brodie, Jocelyn, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Brooks, Karen, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Buffalo, Jo, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Busch, Mary, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Bush, Bob, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bush, Jack/Mabel, 1959-1979, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Bush, Martin, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - B, circa 1939-1982, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Cabot, Judy, 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cabot, Lewis, 1968-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cahana, Alice, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Calkins, Robert, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cammell, Suzanne, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Canadian Art, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Canning, Jaci, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Carmen, E.A., 1972-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Carnedie, Georgia/Jane/Margaret, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Caro, Anthony, 1972-1983, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Carpenter, Ken, 1968-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carrier, David, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Carter, Dean, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cast, David, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Castillejo, Jose Luis, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Castoro, Rosemarie, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Catlin, Stanton, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cervene, Dick, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Champa, Kermit, 1963-1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chattanooga Art Association, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Christensen, Stephanie, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Christian, Susan, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Clarke, Ann, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cohen, Charles, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cohen, Harold, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Colt, Priscilla, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cook, Karen/Ruben, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1966-1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Cornell University, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cornford, Christopher, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Cortella, Gloria, 1960-1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cotton, Judy, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cronin, Robert, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - C, 1963-1983, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Dagbert, Anne, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Danks, Jean, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Darrah, Ann, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Davidson College, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Davis, Gene, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Day, Harold, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - De Broglie, Jeanne-Marie, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - De Morand, Morey, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Detroit Institute of the Arts, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Devade, Mark, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Diebenkorn, Richard, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Donnelly, Tom, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Dorazio, Piero/Virginia, 1963-1983 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Douglas-Henry, James, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Drake, Anstiss, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Drapell, Josef, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dubeffet, Jean, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Duke University, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Durrant, Jennifer, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dyyon, Frazier, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dzubas, Friedel, 1952-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - D, 1962-1983, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Eagle, Johanna, 1968-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Edmondson, Jerilyn, 1970-1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Edmonton Art Gallery, 1963-1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Edwards, Oscar, 1965-1983, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Elderfield, John, 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Elkon, Robert, 1965-1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ellertson, Gabriele, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ellin, Everett, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Elliott, James, 1961-1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Emmerich, Andre, 1964-1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Erasmus, Nel, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Everett, Tricia, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Eyerly, Frank/Jean, 1963-1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - E, 1964-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Falkenheim, Jackie, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Farrelly, John, circa 1949-1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Farwell, Bea, 1963-1982 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Feeley, Paul/Helen, 1955-1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Feist, Harold, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Fenton, Terry, 1965-1983, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
  - Follett, Jean, 1966-1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Forrester, Vera, 1966-1975 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Fourcade, Dominique, 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Fourinier, Paul, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Francis, Sam, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1950-1983, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Freeman, Betty, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Freund, Gisele, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Freund, Tibor, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Freundlich, August, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Fried, Michael, 1963-1971 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Friedman, Bob, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Fuchs, Rudi, 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Furman, Frank/Frieda, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - F, 1937-1982 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Gallus, Agnes, 1973-1982 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Gandhy, Kekoo, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Gaul, Winifred, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Geldzahler, Helen, 1963-1978 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Geoffrey, J. I. Qbal, 1962-1972 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Gerard, Lisa, 1969-1981 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Gerbarg, Darcy, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gibbons, John, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gibbs, David, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gibson, Thomas, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gimpel Fils, 1956-1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gintz, Claude-Hubert, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gladstone, Gerald, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Glusberg, Jorge, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Goldman, Judith, 1969-1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Goodnough, Robert, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gore, Robert, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gottlieb, Adolf, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Graham, Carolyn, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Graham, Donald, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grenville, Bruce, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Griefen, John, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Grosse, Hannes, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Growe, Brendt, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Gruber, Aaronel Deroy, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gruters, William, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1947-1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Guggenheim Musuem, 1964-1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Gulibaut, Serge, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - G, 1947-1982, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Halasz, Piri, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Halbreich, Kathy, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hall, Lee, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hanes, R. Philip, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Harman, Maryann, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Harrison, Charles, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Haynes, Doug, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Held, Jonathan, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Hendersen, Elizabeth, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Henderson, Joseph, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Henning, Edward, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Henry, Douglas, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Herdeg, Klaus, 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Hide, Peter, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Hilton, Roger, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Hilton, Tim, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Hindry, Ann, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Hoesterey, Ingeborg, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Hoffman, George, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Hofmann, Hans, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Holabird, Jean, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Holland Festival, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Hollega, Wolfgang, 1959-1979 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Hollyman, Stephanie, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Hong, Kai, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Hood, Dorothy, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hoppe, Carol, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Horton, Mervyn, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Hosiasson, Philippe, 1968-1976 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Hudson, Andrew, 1962-1982 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Huggins, Victor, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Hughto, Darryl, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Hutchinson, Jay, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - H, 1955-1983, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
  - Israel, 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - I, 1951-1977 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Jablons, Pamela, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Jackson, Herb, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Jenkins, Paul, 1956-1974 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Johnson, Buffie, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Johnson, Daniel Larue, 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - J, 1954-1983 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Kainen, Jacob/Ruth, 1970-1983 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Kalenberg, Angel, 1964-1973 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Kam'bayashi, Sumio, 1966-1974 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Kasmin, LTD., 1963-1977 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Katzen, Lila, 1963-1978 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Kaufman, Basil/Gill, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - King, Phillip, 1964-1978 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Kingsbury, Martha, 1971-1979 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Kinsman, Robert, 1965-1980 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Kipphoff, Petra, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kiyooka, Roy, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Knowles, Dorothy, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Koehn, Lala, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Konopny, Goldie, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Koren, Johannes, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Krasner, Lee, 1956, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Krauss, Rosalind, 1965-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)